<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Donghyun Kim on Donghyun Kim</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Donghyun Kim on Donghyun Kim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Donghyun Kim</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Posts</title>
      <link>/posts-should-be-in-the-home-folder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts-should-be-in-the-home-folder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A longitudinal study of individual differences in the acquisition of new vowel contrasts</title>
      <link>/publication/longitudinal-perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/longitudinal-perception/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual differences in perceptual adaptation to phonetic categories: Categorization gradiency and cognitive abilities</title>
      <link>/talk/asa174/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/asa174/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual differences in perceptual adaptation to phonetic categories: Categorization gradiency and cognitive abilities</title>
      <link>/talk/apcam2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/apcam2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual differences in the link between perception and production and the mechanisms of phonetic imitation</title>
      <link>/publication/perception-production-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/perception-production-link/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptual adaptation to phonetic categories in adverse conditions</title>
      <link>/project/perceptual-adaptation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/perceptual-adaptation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although speech sounds are highly variable and listeners may have limited cognitive resources under adverse conditions, listeners are shown to overcome these challenges by flexibly adapting to these varying situations and achieving an invariant percept. Understanding how listeners overcome these adverse conditions is a fundamental issue for better understanding the mechanisms underlying perceptual learning in speech and more generally speech perception processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to better understand the underlying mechanisms of perceptual adaptation to variability of speech. We examine how listeners overcome challenging conditions and what makes listeners better adapt to variability in both the signal and listening environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A longitudinal study of the acquisition of novel speech sound contrasts</title>
      <link>/project/l2-speech-acquisition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/l2-speech-acquisition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is well known that second language (L2) learners have difficulties in acquiring speech sound contrasts not present in their native language. Some documented difficulties include the English /l/-/ɹ/ contrast for Japanese learners and the English /i/-/ɪ/ contrast for Spanish and Korean learners. This may be related to the observation that native listeners categorize speech sounds using multiple acoustic cues but that, for any given contrast, they pay more attention to certain cues over others; this is referred to as perceptual cue weighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most studies of L2 acquisition of sound categories have focused either on comparing the learning of different contrasts or on the learning of appropriate cue weights for particular contrasts. Most studies have also used cross-sectional approaches to investigate the development of L2 speech acquisition. Moreover, relatively little has been reported on age-related differences in L2 speech acquisition. Taken together, this has limited our understanding of (1) how individuals’ cue weighting strategies change over time, (2) how cue weights are acquired across contrasts, (3) how developmental changes in perception are related to those in production within individual learners, (4) how L2 speech acquisition influences L1 categories over time, and (5) whether adult and child learners show different developmental patterns. The goal of this project is to address these issues using longitudinal data to better understand how individual second language learners differ in their developmental trajectories in the acquisition of novel speech sound contrasts over time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual differences in second language speech perception across tasks and contrasts: The case of English vowel contrasts by Korean learners</title>
      <link>/publication/perception-tasks-contrasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/perception-tasks-contrasts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptual adaptation of atypical vowels</title>
      <link>/talk/pmck2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/pmck2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The link between speech perception and production and the mechanisms of phonetic imitation</title>
      <link>/talk/mot2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/mot2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plain Markdown Post</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-30-hello-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-30-hello-markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a post written in plain Markdown (&lt;code&gt;*.md&lt;/code&gt;) instead of R Markdown (&lt;code&gt;*.Rmd&lt;/code&gt;). The major differences are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot run any R code in a plain Markdown document, whereas in an R Markdown document, you can embed R code chunks (&lt;code&gt;```{r}&lt;/code&gt;);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A plain Markdown post is rendered through &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/overview/configuration/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blackfriday&lt;/a&gt;, and an R Markdown document is compiled by &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rmarkdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://pandoc.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many differences in syntax between Blackfriday&amp;rsquo;s Markdown and Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s Markdown. For example, you can write a task list with Blackfriday but not with Pandoc:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;task-list&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;label&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled class=&#34;task-list-item&#34;&gt; Write an R package.&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;label&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled class=&#34;task-list-item&#34;&gt; Write a book.&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;label&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled class=&#34;task-list-item&#34;&gt; &amp;hellip;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;label&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled class=&#34;task-list-item&#34;&gt; Profit!&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Blackfriday does not support LaTeX math and Pandoc does. I have added the MathJax support to this theme (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yihui/hugo-lithium-theme&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;hugo-lithium-theme&lt;/a&gt;) but there is a caveat for plain Markdown posts: you have to include math expressions in a pair of backticks (inline: &lt;code&gt;`$ $`&lt;/code&gt;; display style: &lt;code&gt;`$$ $$`&lt;/code&gt;), e.g., &lt;code&gt;$S_n = \sum_{i=1}^n X_i$&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:This-is-because&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:This-is-because&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; For R Markdown posts, you do not need the backticks, because Pandoc can identify and process math expressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When creating a new post, you have to decide whether the post format is Markdown or R Markdown, and this can be done via the &lt;code&gt;ext&lt;/code&gt; argument of the function &lt;code&gt;blogdown::new_post()&lt;/code&gt;, e.g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;blogdown::new_post(&amp;quot;Post Title&amp;quot;, ext = &#39;.Rmd&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:This-is-because&#34;&gt;This is because we have to protect the math expressions from being interpreted as Markdown. You may not need the backticks if your math expression does not contain any special Markdown syntax such as underscores or asterisks, but it is always a safer choice to use backticks. When you happen to have a pair of literal dollar signs inside the same element, you can escape one dollar sign, e.g., &lt;code&gt;\$50 and $100&lt;/code&gt; renders &amp;ldquo;\$50 and $100&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:This-is-because&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual differences in the relation between perception and production and the mechanisms of phonetic imitation</title>
      <link>/talk/asa172/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/asa172/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual differences in the relation between perception and production and the mechanisms of phonetic imitation</title>
      <link>/talk/icspa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/icspa/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual differences in second language speech perception across tasks and contrasts</title>
      <link>/talk/labphon15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/labphon15/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual differences in the relation between perception and production and mechanisms of phonetic imitation</title>
      <link>/talk/ksss2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/ksss2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
