<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Donghyun Kim</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Donghyun Kim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Donghyun Kim</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptual adaptation to phonetic categories in adverse conditions</title>
      <link>/project/perceptual-adaptation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/perceptual-adaptation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although speech sounds are highly variable and listeners may have limited cognitive resources under adverse conditions, listeners are shown to overcome these challenges by flexibly adapting to these varying situations and achieving an invariant percept. Understanding how listeners overcome these adverse conditions is a fundamental issue for better understanding the mechanisms underlying perceptual learning in speech and more generally speech perception processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to better understand the underlying mechanisms of perceptual adaptation to variability of speech. We examine how listeners overcome challenging conditions and what makes listeners better adapt to variability in both the signal and listening environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A longitudinal study of the acquisition of novel speech sound contrasts</title>
      <link>/project/l2-speech-acquisition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/l2-speech-acquisition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is well known that second language (L2) learners have diﬀiculties perceiving speech sound contrasts not present in their native language. Some documented diﬀiculties include the English /l/-/ɹ/ contrast for Japanese learners and the English /i/-/ɪ/ contrast for Spanish and Korean learners. This may be related to the observation that native listeners categorize speech sounds using multiple acoustic cues but that, for any given contrast, they pay more attention to certain cues over others; this is referred to as perceptual cue weighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most studies of L2 acquisition of sound categories have focused either on comparing the learning of different contrasts or on the learning of appropriate cue weights for particular contrasts. Most studies have also used cross-sectional approaches to investigate the development of L2 speech acquisition. Moreover, relatively little has been reported on age-related differences in L2 speech acquisition. Taken together, this has limited our understanding of (1) how individuals’ cue weighting strategies change over time, (2) how cue weights are acquired across contrasts, (3) how developmental changes in perception are related to those in production, (4) how L2 speech acquisition influences L1 categories, and (5) whether adult and child learners show different developmental patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to understand how individual second language learners differ in their developmental trajectories in the acquisition of novel speech sound contrasts. We take an individual differences approach using longitudinal data to investigate how individual L2 learners differ in their developmental trajectories over time. We also test whether child and adult learners differ in their acquisition patterns and whether they follow different trajectories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The link between speech perception and production and the mechanisms of phonetic imitation</title>
      <link>/project/perception-production-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/perception-production-link/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As language users who perceive and produce speech sounds, the link between speech perception and production is inherent in our use of spoken language. Although relatively little is known about the nature of this link and whether the same representations are used for both perception and production, understanding how speech perception and production are related is important for better understanding the mechanisms underlying speech perception and production as well as for the better understanding of speech communication in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to better understand how speech perception and production is linked at an individual level. This study investigates the relation between speech perception and production using a phonetic imitation paradigm. We used manipulated stimuli in both perception and production tasks with the goal of more directly exploring the link between the two, and examined (1) whether individual listeners’ perceptual cue weights are related to their patterns of phonetic imitation and (2) the underlying mechanisms of phonetic imitation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
